Guide to the Vietnam War Veterans Archives and History Center records, [ca.1979]-1988.
Vietnam War Veterans Archives and History Center records, [ca.1979]-1988.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Vietnam War Veterans Archives and History Center records, [ca.1979]-1988.
7000
Vietnam War Veterans Archives and History Center.
3.3 cubic ft., 5 cassettes.
Minutes, correspondence, grant proposals, survey project responses, clippings, audiotapes, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records include minutes, correspondence, grant proposals, and survey project responses. Files relating to the Cornell phase of the project include correspondence, clippings, and survey forms. Also includes five tape cassettes.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Vietnam War Veterans Archives and History Center began in 1978 as a project of the Flower of the Dragon, Inc., a veterans outreach group based in California. One aim of the VWV was to establish a repository for materials donated by Vietnam veterans. The Cornell University Archives became that repository in 1981.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records include minutes, correspondence, grant proposals, and survey project responses. Files relating to the Cornell phase of the project include correspondence, clippings, and survey forms. Also includes five tape cassettes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Vietnam War Veterans Archives and History Center.; Flower of the Dragon.; Vietnam War Veterans Archives.
Subjects:
Soldiers.; Veterans.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Part of the Vietnam War Veterans Archives.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Archives Project Records
  - Flower of the Dragon Board Minutes, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Flower of the Dragon Board Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Inventory of Books Purchased or Donated to VWV (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters of Support (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vietnam Veteran Writers Conference Concept Paper (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Budgets Submitted to Foundations, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Original Written Outline and Projected Budget (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - VWV Concept Paper (submitted to foundations), 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - VWV Funding Proposal (submitted to foundations), 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - VWV Concept Papers (submitted to foundations), 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Funding Inquiry (submitted to foundations), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - VWV Summaries and Miscellaneous Originals (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Media Coverage - Archives Project (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Media Coverage - Symposium (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Veterans Research (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Subseries 1. Advisory Board
    - CVS Information (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Archival Advisory Board Meeting Tapes ( Sept. 1, 1981, San Francisco) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - First National Advisory Board Meeting Tapes ( June 4, 1980, Washington, DC) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Advisory Board Reports (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Anderson, Paul (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Blank, Arthur (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bonfield, Lynn A. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Crandell, Bill (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Crawford, Donald (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Credle, James (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Emerson, Gloria (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Figley, Charles (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Fleckner, John (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Gelb, Leslie (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Geylin, Philip (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Harrison, Donald (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Hersh, Seymour (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Lewis, Karen (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Lifton, Robert Jay (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Lindley, Rusty (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Phillips, Dean (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Rhoades, Dennis (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Slotkin, Helen (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Subseries 2. Archives and Libraries
    - A-B (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - C-D (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - California State Archives, correspondence (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - E-F (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - G-H (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - I-J (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - K-L (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - M-N (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - O-P (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Q-R (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - S-T (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - U-V (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - W, X, Y, Z (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Subseries 3. CVS
    - CVS Board of Directors Reports, Corres. (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - CVS - Package Sent to Board Members (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Subseries 4. Cornell
    - Cornell - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Subseries 5. General
    - A-B (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - C-D (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - E-F (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - G-H (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - I-J (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - K-L (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - M-N (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - O-P (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Q-R (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - S-T (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Thompson, Leroy - Bookdealer (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - U-V (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - W-Z (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Subseries 6. Military
    - Air Force (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Army (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Army - Military Academy at West Point (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Marine Corps (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Navy (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Navy - Naval Academy at Annapolis (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Subseries 7
    - A-B (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - C-D (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - E-F (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - G-H (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - I-J (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - K-L (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - M-N (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - O-P (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Q-R (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - S-T (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - U-V (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - W-X (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Y-Z (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Series III. Funding Requests - Outstanding
  - Subseries 1. Foundations
    - Foundations - Requests A-B (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Columbia Foundations (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Foundations - Requests C-D (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Foundations - Requests E-F (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Foundations - Requests G-H (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Gerbode Foundation (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Foundations - Requests I-J (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Foundations - Requests M-N (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Foundations - Requests O-P (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Foundations - Requests Q-R (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Foundations - Requests S-T (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Foundations - Requests U-V (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Foundations - Requests W-X (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Foundations - Requests Y-Z (Box 1, Folder 100)
- Series IV. Funding Requests - NEH
  - Subseries 1. NEH Funding Proposals
    - NEH Funding Proposal, Initial - Oct. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - NEH Funding Proposal, Revised - Dec. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - NEH Reviewer's Comments - Dec. 1979 Proposal (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Subseries 2. NEH - First Phase
    - Award Letter - First Phase (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - NEH - Budget, First Phase (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - NEH Correspondence, First Phase (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - NEH Final Report, First Phase (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Subseries 3. NEH - Second Phase
    - NEH Award Letter, Second Phase (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - NEH Budget, Second Phase (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - NEH Correspondence, Second Phase (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - NEH Narrative of Accomplishments - Reports (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Pilot Survey Returns (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series V. NHPRC
  - Subseries 1. NHPRC Correspondence
    - NHPRC Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - NHPRC - Funding Proposal, Initial, Sept. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - NHPRC - Funding Proposal, Revised, Oct. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - NHPRC - Reviewer's Comments, Oct. 1979 Proposal (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - NHPRC - Funding Proposal - July 1980 Reviewer's Comments (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - NHPRC - Funding Proposal - July 1980 Response to Reviewers Comments (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 2. NHPRC - Phase I
    - NHPRC Award Letter, Phase I (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - NHPRC Budget, Phase I (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - NHPRC Narrative Reports, Phase I (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 3. NHPRC - Phase II
    - NHPRC Award Letter, Phase II (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - NHPRC Budget, Phase II (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - NHPRC Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - NHPRC Funding Proposal, July 1, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - NHPRC Grant Regulations (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - NHPRC Narrative Reports, Phase II (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series VI. Survey Project
  - Subseries 1. Donor Materials
    - Biographical Information Sheet (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Certificate of Gift (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Donor Instructions (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 2. Donor Requests Letters
    - Donor Request Letter (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Subseries 3. Initial Follow-Up Letters
    - Initial Follow-Up Letter (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 4. Thank You Notes (No Donation)
    - Thank You Notes (No Donation) (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series VII. Survey Responses
  - Subseries 1. Survey Correspondence - Individual
    - A-B (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - C-D (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - E-F (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - G-H (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - I-J (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - K-L (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - M-N (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - O-P (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Q-R (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - S-T (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - U-V (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - W-X (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Y-Z (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 2. No Materials - No Response Necessary
    - No Materials/No Donation (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 3. Yes Materials - No response Necessary
    - No Response Necessary (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 4. Yes Materials/No Donor Follow-Up Necessary
    - A (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - B (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - C (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - D (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - E (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - F (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - G (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - H (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - I (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - J (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - K (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - L (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - M (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - N (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - O (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - P (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Q (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - R (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - S (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - T (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - U (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - V (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - W (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - X, Y, Z (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Subseries 5. Positive Responses General Follow-Up
    - A (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - B (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - C (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - D (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - E (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - F (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - G (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - H (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - I (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - J (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - K (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - L (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - M (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - N (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - O (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - P (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Q (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - R (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - S (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - T (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - U (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - V (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - W (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - X, Y, Z (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - No Follow-Up Possible (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Subseries 6. Selected Donors
    - A (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - B (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - C (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - D (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - E (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - F (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - G (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - H (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - I (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - J (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - K (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - L (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - M (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - N (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - O (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - P (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Q (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - R (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - S (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - T (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - U (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - V (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - W (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - X, Y, Z (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - No Follow-Up Possible (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Subseries 7. Postcard Responses
    - Index cards (Box 3)
- Unprocessed material (Box 4)